# Joshua Dyer

Alabama, United States jdyer.jsg@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Parkway Medical Center — Research Coordinator

November 2020 - PRESENT

Perform and manage research activities including patient visits, scheduling, managing of source documents, data entry, query resolution and correspondence with both study managers and patients. Maintain Investigator Site Files. Correspond and manage communication with the Institutional Review Board (IRB).

## **JSG Medical**, Hanceville, AL — Owner and Chief Sonographer

2016 - PRESENT

Perform ultrasound studies, manage logistics and scheduling, facilitate radiology reports, manage maintenance of equipment as well as the office and all records. Treated as a division of this business, Computing Solutions was absorbed and continues to do business as IT Solutions by JSG, and continues to provide its original services with the addition of web design.

# Parkway Medical Center, Birmingham, AL—Sonographer

2001 - PRESENT

Perform ultrasound studies at the clinic of Dr. James G. Sullivan. Assist in patient care and maintenance of equipment.

# **Summit Internal Medicine,** Birmingham, AL— Sonographer

2006 - PRESENT

Perform ultrasound studies at the clinic of Dr. David F. Wynne. Assist in patient care and maintenance of equipment.

# Pinnacle Mobile Imaging, Vinemont, AL— Chief Sonographer

2001 - 2014

Performed mobile ultrasound studies, not limited to but including echocardiograms, vascular ultrasound and routine ultrasound of the abdomen, pelvis and thyroid. Managed logistics of having studies read and reports delivered. Oversight of other technologists' studies before sending out for interpretation. Managed contacts with several accounts. Assisted with scheduling and route management.

## **Battleground Gaming, Cullman**, AL — Owner and Operator

2008 - 2014

Offered retail games and hobby items. Hosted on-site games and events. Coordinated national events with suppliers to allow local participation in the wider gaming community. Installed and managed software that allowed communication and participation with national and international companies that provided support for the games chosen for local events.

## **Computing Solutions**, Cullman, AL — Owner and Technician

2000 - 2010

Perform upgrades and maintenance for medical ultrasound equipment. Perform installation, upgrades, maintenance, and repair of home and small office computers and computer networks.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **High School:**

Vinemont High School, Vinemont, AL 1984 - 1997

# College:

#### The University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL 1997 - 2003

Computer and Information Science, Mathematics, Biology

## Jefferson State Community College, Birmingham, AL 2016-2018

**Biology** 

## Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT 2023 - Current

Pursuing Bachelors of Science of Information Technology

#### **Additional Education:**

#### FreeCodeCamp.org 2022-Current

Interactive Web Design

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

# Udemy, 2014-Current

Canva Designers Course, Mitch Stevens

Computer Science 101, Kurt Anderson

Discovering Godot, Ben Tristem

Java Programming Master Class, Tim Buchalka

#### **Credentials**

Registered Vascular and Cardiac Sonographer through the ARDMS (Registry #94974) - certified 2002

Member of the Society of Diagnostic Medical Sonographers (Member #083833)

# FreeCodeCamp.org, 2023 - Current

Responsive Web Design Certificate, Currently pursuing Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures Certificate

## CompTIA, 2023 - Current

Pursuing A+ Certification

#### **Projects**

My Portfolio Webpage: <a href="https://joshua-dyer.github.io/portfolio/">https://joshua-dyer.github.io/portfolio/</a>

Git Repository: <a href="https://github.com/joshua-dyer">https://github.com/joshua-dyer</a>

Repl.it Projects: <a href="https://replit.com/@JoshuaDyer9">https://replit.com/@JoshuaDyer9</a>

Current projects include use of Python, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, and SQL. See my portfolio webpage for more details!

#### About me

Joshua Dyer is currently working as a clinical research coordinator at Parkway Medical Center, LLC, under the guiding assistance of the Primary Investigator James Sullivan, M.D. He is currently also managing a small business that provides ultrasound services to several local medical clinics. Prior to opening his own business, Joshua was the chief sonographer of Pinnacle Mobile Imaging, the company that he originally began his ultrasound career with in 2001. Prior to this, Joshua had studied computer science at the University of Alabama at Birmingham. Technology was his original focus, but while working part time during college, he found that he enjoyed working in healthcare and assisting in the care of patients. He has continued to study and learn in both medicine and technology throughout his life and has managed a comfortable competency in both. With the more recent opportunity to experience clinical research, he finds it an interesting blend of medicine, data science, and technology, and has set his path accordingly to further develop technical and management skills.

Updated 17 February, 2024